uh the pot is very
hot and then you reach out and you grab
the pot uh and you get
burned
then only very stupid
person will yell at the pot you a bad
pot you burn me you know like that okay
like only stupid person will will yell
at the pot in the same way
uh that person who get angry at another
person who hurt them is stupid okay got
it the people who hurt you are like the
cooking pot okay and uh who made the
cooking pot hot you made the cooking pot
hot if you want to get upset you can get
upset at
yourself okay all right good
and those of you who study DCI we use
this in DCI right and there's a what's
the other part of this
example
H
yeah person grabbed the pot and it it's
hot it's burn their hand and they're
like I hate you I hate you ah I hate you
I hate
you stupid just open your hand like go
okay like they say oh the pot burned me
okay just let go of the pot okay then we
are like that oh he hurt me he hurt me
you know okay just get out of the house
go to the coffee shop you know avoid
this person you know don't don't don't
like hold the hot thing and oh it hurts
so much shut up let go you know okay
don't keep whining about it
okay it is the nature of fire to burn
you fire cannot help Fire's nature you
cannot complain to the fire and say I
want you to be ice
cream you know that's not the nature of
fire okay Fire's nature to burn
something okay then don't blame the
fire that it burn you you know you're
the stupid person who hold the fire okay
so let go of the fire don't yell at the
fire the fire has to burn people
listen after
71.9 years of
life I will tell you some deep Buddhist
truth stupid people people are stupid
people and they will hurt you okay so
you are stupid if you if you stay near
them if you keep holding on to that and
and they keep burning you and you keep
holding on to that then that's not their
fault it's your fault okay just get out
of the house go someplace else you
know when I have a bad day in my
business my I'm in business 19 years
commuting 4 hours on the bus every day
okay when I have a
bad day I have bad time with somebody I
just go to the
bathroom and go in the special seat and
talk to Future Buddha
Mike okay and you don't don't stay with
angry people don't don't live with angry
people
just avoid them okay don't don't don't
hurt yourself okay let go of the fire
okay don't get angry at them then then
you create more okay in
Buddhism if you get angry at the people
who hurt you you create more people who
hurt you so it doesn't help it doesn't
help to fight with anybody never just
get out of the room go someplace else
you know go sit in the toilet talk to
Future Buddha M or future Buddha bill or
who whoever it is okay
cool all
right okay listen I understand that it's
the nature of
fire to burn me I understand that but
this person especially [__] today you
know I understand his name natur is fire
I understand he's going to hurt me but
seems like he's making special effort to
hurt me okay uh
on here here's the word s s
okay and you kind of know what it is
some of you word prob know yeah hail
okay the ice that falls from the sky
it's called yeah cam isans you know the
old
expression yeah I would have to mention
it okay all right sh
okay
uh if somebody hurts you if someone hits
you if someone says bad things to you
and causes you suffering okay
uh and then you as an answer you hurt
them back or you say also bad thing to
them okay someone call you stupid and
you say I'm not stupid you stupid okay
that's a cause to take a bad rebirth
after you die that's a specific cause to
go to the hell Realms
okay gu I don't believe in the hell
Realms okay I'll see you there all
[Music]
right you want a cute
story um this is why you have Grandpa to
teach you um so my teacher
taught uh in two places he taught in New
York area and he taught in Washington DC
area he had a small group there I was
his driver so I always go with him I I
always take him down there you know and
he he went down he went there for we
went there together for over 20
years uh like once a month he go down
and teach for four or five days and uh
I'm the driver and he taught them for
many years this
book okay and then he
said because we finished this book I'm
willing to teach you some secret
teaching okay he said because we
finished the book I'm willing to teach
you some Diamond Wade teaching you
understand what I'm
saying then
[Applause]
[Laughter]
yeah so actually we will finish this
book then I'm
unemployed maybe I have to retire no uh
so next year i' like to teach you some
Diamond weight teaching if you want and
uh
there are many good teachers that I
taught for many years 20 years 30 years
uh John Connie
Gala cat I I taught these people uh
Diamond W from many years I taught them
14year Diamond W course seven-year
preparation seveny year Diamond way
course
okay and I told them at that time I'm
not teaching it again you teach it okay
and I kept that promise I didn't teach
it uh since then and they teach it and I
asked them to continue and I'm very
happy that they are teaching and they
are teaching it good they are doing a
good job I don't need to teach it okay
uh they are teaching the Deep
correct 30,000 pages okay translation
that grandpa taught and I encourage you
to take that kind of teaching okay
but if you also want to do some relaxed
Diamond way with
Grandpa like your real
Grandpa uh then we can do together okay
next year but uh please continue to do
the if you if you're a serious person
please continue to do the diamond way
with other with my students who teach
okay uh that's
the so that's the smart thing to do do
the do the Deep Diamond way course the
real course 14 years
okay uh seven years preparation seven
years course
uh but if you just want to have fun with
Grandpa and do some Diamond way let's do
next year okay agree all right
[Music]
okay and Tim Tim will arrange everything
Tim and his staff he
disappeared he they'll arrange
everything right where is Tim he
disappeared see always give your
students work when they are not
there okay uh yeah okay now the real
story so I'm the driver for my teacher
he went down to his small group in
Washington DC
for 30 years something and then he teach
them Diamond way and uh you have to take
uh
some initiation and you have to take the
vows you have to promise to keep the
vows there's some vows you promise you
have to
make and then uh so he announced he's
going to teach The Vow he's going to
give the vow and we went down to special
lady's house she has a she's a rich
lady she's actually Professor uh at a
university in Washington and um she said
come to my
house and and we can do the vows at my
house you know and so we went there I
remember uh we were cooking uh before
the
ceremony and she she told me uh I want
to say something to the
teacher and uh I said uh okay what what
do you want to say I'm his
translator but Gua he speak
English I translate his English into
English okay so I have to be there then
she said to him uh but by the way he
started to learn English when he was
almost my age so it's unbelievable he
learned English but sometimes he needs
some help so he he she she said uh
please tell teacher I want to give him
my house tonight uh before the ceremony
you know and and I translate you know
I'm
like she want to give you it's a Beau
house in in expensive very expensive
North North Virginia this is close
to some big government places anyway so
he's like um then I finally he
understand and he said no and I'm
like and he's like no I said he's like
no I don't want it you know I won't take
your house you keep your house you know
then then I was
like because at that time we just at
that trip uh our car is so old it broke
down and it blew up and there was a big
fire in in the highway and uh I'm
like and he's
like you know Let it go I'm like okay
you know we were very poor at that time
and then I'm like okay that's all right
then he then she said we cook some more
and then she said
um can I can I ask another question and
I said I he said yeah you can ask she
said uh tonight you will give Diamond
way commitment Diamond way vows and he
said
yes and uh she said I heard that if you
break your diamond way commitments you
go directly to Hell R you spent long
time in the hill he said that's correct
then she said I don't think I want to
take the
V then he said oh no no don't worry
you're going to hell
anyway then she's like what he said you
going to hell anyway all of you going to
hell you know and he's she's like
well why then he said take the V break
the V then when you get to the hell and
you guys are in the fire
together and you talking what did you do
to go to hell I killed 10 people what
did you do to go to hell I stole my
parents money what you do to go to hell
I took
initiation Diamond way I'm here because
I did Diamond way
wrong then you can be proud you know
you're the best person in the
hell just
kidding okay why did I say that um oh
uh yeah so you cannot fight all the bad
people in the world it's not possible
okay by the way you have a
responsibility if someone is hurting
somebody else you it's your
responsibility to help okay like like we
have Refugee from Ukraine in in my me
and my wife support several and it's
very expensive and it's very difficult
but if someone's in trouble if someone's
really suffering we have responsibility
to to help them if someone's hurting
another person we have responsibility to
help that person we must help that
person but uh we don't have
responsibility to hurt anybody okay we
we do not have responsibility to to hurt
another person that's that's crazy
that's not Buddhism okay understand
different different thing
okay then he quotes
uh if you
cannot if you cannot be peaceful with
the angry
person if you say look guess I agree you
know someone hurt you you you shouldn't
hurt them I agree but this one person is
too
much by the way everybody has a too much
person yeah guess lot generally I agree
someone hurt you you you shouldn't hurt
them but this person I have they are
different everyone in the world thinks
they are different you know no you don't
understand llama I have the worst
husband in the world you know no you
don't understand I met 1,000 worst
husband in the world
already okay it's not true okay so
anyway here it says uh try to
understand you know either you can try
to
be pleasant when someone's hurting you
try to be patient with them or you can
go to the hell and suffer for a million
years which is
easier which one is easier you know like
there's no person who's so there's no
husband who's so bad they're worse than
a million years in hell maybe 100,000
years but there's no husband so bad
there's no wife so bad
that uh they are they are worse than a
million years in the hell and if you get
angry at them you go to the hell and you
stay there long time it's
better before you go to hell it's better
to not do it you know and
just just you know be skillful
Buddhism
Pap be skillful be skillful you know
like change the subject get out of the
house do something else you know is it
wrong to get a divorce in Buddhism no
it's not wrong if someone's hurting you
that's fine okay my mom did that uh and
and that that's you're not supposed to
get hurt okay but you're not you're not
supposed to get angry either okay you
have to take care of yourself and and
don't don't don't put yourself in a
worse place than this guy CU there are
worst places it's called hell okay all
right uh next
picture yeah good this is a picture I
enjoy choosing these pictures I choose
the pictures to help you remember the
class so if you're
smart get Tim to share the pictures with
you or take a picture on your
phone by the way I paid for the pictures
they're all legal it's legal for you to
use them okay uh and
uh you can remember the class better
from the picture than from trying to
remember what gisha said okay the
picture is something to remind you of
the class and I suggest you keep the
pictures and what I do I have them on my
phone when I I I go for a walk every day
in Kyoto
and I walk around the city and I I look
at pictures on my phone and I test
myself you know do you remember the
picture with all the hands touching each
other yeah what's that mean in gisha
class don't remember actually I I test
myself every day I get the picture and I
take it with me on a walk I have it here
and and I test myself with the picture
so I suggest
you test yourself with the picture you
know uh
legally especially if you want to study
Diamond
way you are required to review the class
twice after the class once right after
the class once the next day that's a
requirement to enter Diamond way okay so
just easy way take a picture of the
picture look at it tonight say okay I
remember remember the the hands thing I
remember what G said and then next day
when you wake up you're having
breakfast you know you can be one of
those
people they all wasting their time with
the news you are studying LM again you
know okay and uh check yourself okay
that's why I used and it takes a long
time to choose the pictures so don't
waste my time
okay if you get more chances to practice
your patience you will be a better
person therefore you should pray to the
Buddhist that they send you as many as
holes as
possible okay but don't forget you ask
for it okay don't complain later you
know God I used to have a few irritating
people in my life now I have [__]
Everywhere You Know by the way can I
tell you another
joke okay I taught this subject at
diamond
mountain and
uh and we spent a long time explaining
uh that irritating people come from your
own Karma okay and uh every time you
meet a irritating person you're actually
seeing a mirror of yourself okay like
every time you meet a person who hurts
you every time you meet a person who
makes you upset you're are actually
looking in a mirror you know and uh so
anyway a new student came to diamond
mountain and they finally they
the it was the next day and they they
didn't hear the class the day
before and then they said uh there's a
idiom in English uh we say I'm
surrounded by idiots you know everyone
around me is an idiot you know and we
asked her did you enjoy your your time
at di mountain and she said no I had a
terrible time and we said why and she
said I'm surrounded by idiots you know
then we all
like it means when you say I'm
surrounded by idiots you are saying I'm
an idiot because you create those people
so the more [__] in your life the
bigger [__] is
you understand okay all right that's an
old diamond mountain
joke NJ
therefore when people hurt you I don't
know like you go into business with
somebody and uh I don't know I have a
business I have lots of
businesses and uh you know I try to find
people who are good with I try to find
people who like accounting because I
hate
accounting like even I go bankrupt I
refuse to look at accounting you know I
it you know people said Ellie's always
telling me you have no idea what's going
on with your accounts I'm like and I
don't want to know I don't care you know
but you should look at least you should
look at it I'm like no I don't want to
I'm busy I'm translating you know I I
have this thing I hate
accounting so I try to find business
partners who are good with money and
they know how to keep the money and they
they always say oh we got lots you know
the money is good we got money I'm like
God bless I love you you know I don't
want to look at it you know
therefore I think it's important in a
business you find people you can make a
what do you call
collaboration you know like they do the
accounting you do the dinner
parties like that I I that's the kind of
collaboration I
enjoy if you can be
patient with a irritating person who try
to hurt you that's the biggest profit
you can make okay you are burning up Bad
Karma every minute okay every minute you
don't get
upset every minute you don't get angry
you are burning
up Bad Karma like Fast really fast
therefore if you're a real Buddhist you
should be happy when you surrounded by
[__] cuz so many chances to burn up
Bad Karma I'm so grateful to you why
you're such an [__] I'm burning up so
much bad karma you know do you have any
friends you want to bring you know also
to the class you know and we can we can
make a collaboration it's like finding
an accountant
it's like finding five people who like
accting you know
understand okay that's the picture now
you understand the picture we got the
picture the last picture yeah that's the
picture got it it's a collaboration you
be the [__] I'll be the bully
SAA okay we we can make music
together okay I need you you need me
okay it's perfect
okay no I want to be surrounded by Buddy
sa a shut up okay
Jo this is a varation on an old story
that you heard many times
about uh AA and his
student but here's a slightly different
one okay uh in the time of AA there was
a
king it's probably gavya gavia it's
probably gab a shing there was a very
uh aesan knew a king and the King had a
very irritating assistant
okay and I'm not talking about my
okay it's just an example in the
book uh adisha asked this King why you
keep such an
irritating attendant why you keep such
an assistant around you and the King
said I reach the Perfection of patience
with this [__] he's extremely
valuable to me understand I always keep
him as close as possible that's why my
wife married me
probably okay
uh yeah
go okay if you're a a real uh budhist
SAA sorry if you're not a buddhis sappa
and you have no interest in being a
buddhis sappa and you are a lower
Buddhist you are a lower practitioner of
Buddhism okay and uh you're still not
supposed to get upset at people okay
even if you never heard of buddhis SAA
even if you never heard of six
Perfections still on the lower lower
Buddhism you still supposed to be
patient with other people
okay loia so needless to
say if we made a
promise to help every living being in
the whole universe you know if we made
this bod serice promise okay to help
every living being in the in the
universe then obviously you should be
patient with with with difficult people
okay you you're not just the normal
Buddhist you are the kind of Buddhist
who promis to help every living being
then it's embarrassing if you get upset
at somebody this this person who hurt
you they're one of your
clients you know you're bodh SAA you
have
clients right
[__] okay
then everyone you get is your client
okay you can't get rid of your clients
okay you have to serve your class that's
bodh sappa that's bodh sappa okay and
then he said it's like the famous uh
Saint Chong Sida called a super MOA okay
super m means Mr
patience and this is a story found in
the diamond cutor Sutra okay it strange
story in the middle of The Diamond
Cutter Sutra okay the things that should
be in The Diamond Cutter Sutra are not
there the things that shouldn't be in
The Diamond Cutter are there okay the
word diamond is not mentioned once in
the diamond cutor Sutra okay strange all
right I trust the book because of the
title okay cut the diamond right okay
but there's also this weird story about
this guy and uh he's out meditating
under a tree and this queen comes
by and she's very
religious and she sees the guy
meditating under a tree and she says can
you teach me
Buddhism because she has a lot of faith
and he says you know okay I I'll share
something with you and they he starts to
teach her under the tree then the king
shows
up and he's very jealous guy and he
thinks they're doing something wrong you
know he gets very angry and then he's
he's like who are you and the guy says
I'm a meditator he says I'll give you
something to meditate
on okay all right
he said tie this guy up okay tie him up
cut off his fingers they start to cut
off his fingers no no no that's not how
you cut somebody's fingers off start
with the end and go a little bit by each
time you know let's let's cut him off
slow let's do a good job you know and
then he cuts all the fingers off and
then then he says okay let's do his
hands okay cut his hands you know then
they say he's still got a el oh let's
cut them down to the Elbow you know and
they he says what are you doing cutting
his elbow you forgot his legs he's got
toes Also let's cut his toes off and
slowly he cut off all the all the toes
all the feet all the hands all the arms
and then uh he asked this guy are you
still meditating honey and the guy says
yes I am and and he he says are you sure
you're still meditating he said yes I am
how I'm not upset at you at all okay I
have no hatred towards you I love you
like my own mother he said to the king
he said to the king you know I I love
you as I love my own mother you know you
are one of
my clients I'm Voda you are one of my
clients you can cut everything off I
don't care you know I I I made a promise
to take care of you guys and you're just
one of my clients I I can't reject the
CL if by the way if you're in a real
business and you reject a client who's
irritating you will have no
clients
right so he's like no I love you I still
love you and and I'll still take care of
you okay and he did all right and that's
a story uh in in shanada he's uh Mr
patience
talker and uh and that's his story from
The Diamond Cutter sura okay it's a very
beautiful story and here it's mentioned
in the larm room okay Tim Tim how are
I'm
doing
s I have no
time seriously okay good I I just forget
what happened time okay I'm sorry uh we
still
have yeah but that means I have to look
at it okay okay here we
go
okay is
NE now we're at a very important part of
this L RM because we are in the
Perfection of patience which is which
number third Perfection of not getting
upset
and I don't know if you remember but
when we started this Perfection we said
uh there's two kinds of patients and
even the English word patience has two
flavors okay it has two different
meanings really one means don't get
angry at other
people and the other one means don't get
frustrated it's different you know he's
very patient he took three years to to
make this painting or something like
that see there it's not like you're
angry at the painting even in
English uh the word patience covers two
things uh and I'm sorry to keep saying
asshoel if you tell my wife I said
[__] even
once I will get
upset uh so anyway there's two kinds of
patience right one is to be patient with
irritating people but the other is to be
patient with things right like it it
rains on like you're you're John Brady
or you're gishi Michael and you have air
conditioning on the top and then it's
raining you know by the way when you
have air conditioning on the top and you
go out in the rain it's
like okay we studied it in hat yoga pipa
what's it called
NADA the sacred
sound the inner
sound okay then that's not a person
right uh so part of Buddhist patience is
to be patient with things and with tasks
with jobs that people give you like like
I don't know if you're working on a very
difficult
translation and and you have to be
patient you know it's not like you're
going to get angry at the at the at some
copper or something it's not it doesn't
mean that it means it hurts to sit there
for five hours and and it hurts to stare
at the computer for five hours and it
hurts your hands really hurt if you do
it five hours a day and uh you have to
be patient with it you have to what do
you call
that it's not really patience it's just
kind of don't get upset you
know you can say endurance but it's
like something difficult and you just
happily keep going happy keep going okay
the third Perfection includes both the
third Perfection includes don't get
upset at people and situations but it
also
includes be willing to have pain if the
goal is important okay and that's just
if you want to be a successful business
person you want to be a successful
Buddhist you want to be a successful
person you have to learn to deal with
pain and and you have to deal with it
gracefully you know do your hands hurt
gisha yes does your stomach hurt right
now yes where they cut yes uh you don't
seem upset no I'm quite
happy okay it's training you you you got
to have training okay and and stuff
happens you can't prevent it it
rains you know things happen bad things
happen and then a real Buddhist is like
I don't care I'm doing something cool
you know I'm busy I'm not going to sit
and worry complain about how I have a
cold or you know I don't have money this
week or I'm not worried about that stuff
I have bigger things to think about okay
so a real Buddhist is a tough guy okay
tough
girl okay tough person okay and and and
I'm not
saying you know I mean a a
real Buddhist is not like me a real
Buddhist doesn't tell
anybody you know like they got
cancer you know they broke their leg and
they're like your mom calls you and
you're like yeah I'm fine everything's
fine you know and they feel fine and
they look fine and they feel happy you
know is your leg broken yes why are you
so happy people ask me that all the time
you just lost all this money why are you
so happy what should I be unhappy will
it give me the money
back understand okay listen stuff
happens I almost said something
else stuff
happens okay you have a choice you can
be you know you can whine you can
complain or you can have a goddamn good
time you know guess I can't believe it
you just had I just got home from
surgery you know I had surgery two days
ago
and I'm sitting there having fun with my
friends and they're like it doesn't it
hurt I'm like yeah it hurts like hell
and they're like well why you goofing
around I said what else you want me to
do you want me to be grumpy you want to
be angry will that help me you know it
won't help anything you know why not be
happy no matter what happens around
you why not be in a good mood all the
time why not why should the world tell
you when to be in a good mood and when
to be in a bad mood you tell the world
I'm in a I'm in a good mood and I don't
care if you're if you're if you want to
be if you want a duck duck on my head
today go ahead godamn it I'm gonna be
happy you know there's no reason not to
be and there's no one forcing you to be
unhappy you see what I mean you you're
the one who
decides oh that's all that's all I can
take now I'm divorced you know that's
all I drew a line you know you're the
one who makes the line why not be why
not enjoy everything you know who said
you couldn't I love to do things they
told me I can't do ever since I was a
kid you know so I'm GNA be happy no
matter what happens today I'm gonna
enjoy the day and I'm not going to let
the day tell me how to be okay got it
that's the second kind of Buddhist
Perfection of patience okay and it's in
the book I didn't make it up okay I'm
just using
it all
right means when when stuff happens when
bad stuff happens just embrace it kiss
it welcome what you know I don't know
doctor just said you need an
operation let's do it man okay I was
joking with the
anesthesiologist we had such a good time
he's like you're a strange guy you know
the kidney doctor said what they say you
were
there yeah yeah she says this is gonna
happen to you this is gonna happen to
you this is gonna happen to you this is
gonna happen to you I'm like yeah okay
and then she looked at me and she said
do you meditate I maybe you know she
she's like I just told you you know and
I'm like yeah okay anyway it does
doesn't help to be upset right why not
just have a good time all
right and that is a Buddhist practice I
didn't make it up okay but I'm using it
and it's it's a lot of fun have fun all
the time okay when the poop hits the fan
have fun all
right ready for the
picture yeah gen means alen in Sanskrit
what is that Jew jewelry jewelry
okay and the book says wear your
troubles like a diamond
ring okay look at look at this diamond
here you know what's that oh the kidney
doctor told me you know bad news
today it's like a diamond you know it's
like a a Jew Jewel wear it like a jewel
you know look check this out check this
thing out like
why you know you're the one who decides
whether to be happy or
sad so if it doesn't help to be unhappy
why not just have a good time with the
kidney you know like hey how you doing
not too good yeah stupid you know okay
when you get trouble trying to do
something
beautiful you should see the trouble
like a diamond ring okay and Mena
means take it like medicine okay when
you get trouble trying to do something
in your
life take it like medicine okay I don't
know why but most medicine tastes
bad okay and it helps you a lot most
suffering
tastes bad but it makes you if you use
it the right way it can make you really
happy okay and that's a strange idea and
you have to get used to it okay the
worst trouble in your life I predict
will be the thing that makes you the
happiness okay and when you get to be 72
you'll
understand okay the worst troubles in
your
life are the things that can make you
the happiest okay if you have a Buddhist
attitude okay all right
Church
uh you know being patient with your
Buddhism okay being patient with your
own Buddhism you know I I can't meditate
it's not working you know I I I sit down
to meditate all I can think about is my
ex-husband you know uh you know Church
go means be patient with
yourself okay as you try to be a
Buddhist one of the kinds of patience is
not with other people one of the kinds
of patience is with yourself okay it's
very hard to change a human being if if
you come into this if you live this life
a little better than when you came in
you are making huge progress you are
very unusual by the way okay if if
you're heart is more open on the last
day in this life than your heart was in
the first days of your life you made
progress just a little bit okay if
you're just a little bit happier when
you die than when you were young then
you made progress you you are unusual
person you're actually unusual person
okay the goal of Buddhism is to go out a
little happier than when you came in and
and then you're a special person that
makes you a special person
okay people hurt
you even you have a problem in a dream
embrace it okay get to be such a good
Buddhist that when someone hurts you in
a dream you're like that's cool thanks
you know are you upset no
I'm okay okay if you can
be patient if who's you got to turn your
phone
off okay if you can be patient with
somebody no uh if you can be patient in
a dream you're getting good okay you're
getting good by the way one of the
Advanced Signs of emptiness
understanding is when you are patient in
a
dream okay uh if you're in a dream and
someone hurts you and you say oh that's
coming the pen is coming from me the pen
is not coming from the pen if you can
say that to yourself in a dream then
you're you're getting to be your
meditation getting good okay if you can
be patient if you can remember not to
get angry in a dream then your Buddhism
is doing pretty good okay all right all
right Lo
people who hurt you even in a dream are
your what do you call it collaborators
okay they are your colleagues in the
thing called
life in the thing called being a
Buddhist irritating people are your
colleagues they are your collaborators
it's like you're creating a new product
together called Buddhism Buddha
buddhahood
okay all
right you should
congratulate every [__] you meet
because by irritating you they are
helping you use up more Bad Karma they
are your what do you call it
coworker okay thanks a lot what you're
such an [__] you know what yeah you
know how much bad Karma I burned up just
by being with you the last 10 minutes
you know thanks so much you know okay
now you have a new way to insult other
people I like it
okay when people give you trouble and I
think we all experienced this when
people give you trouble or when you get
a medical problem like I never much care
about doctors until this year or
something you know I I'm not interested
I don't care you know but when I got
trouble then I'm much more sensitive to
other people who have who who have
problems you see what I mean so you can
think that every time you get a new
problem you are getting some education
in your Buddhism okay every time you get
a new kind of problem you should be
grateful because it's making you a
better Buddhist okay all
right also try to appreciate that if you
met the same
karma in in another lifetime it would
probably be
worse okay in this lifetime you're a
human
so the problems that happen to you are
human problems you know but you go to
other
worlds by the way I I stayed I went to
uh
Moscow uh the first time I went to
Moscow I
no or St Petersburg we we were uh
cataloging books in St Petersburg Russia
and that was just after the Soviet Union
and all foreigners were required to stay
in uh KGB Hotel a secret service Hotel
so they could watch you and every
employee was
KGB and U it was fun I mean it's weird
even the maids are KGB like they're
looking to your suitcase and you're I'm
like go ahead you know it's okay and and
then the day I stayed in the Moscow
Hotel it
has a th rooms or something like that so
you know the Soviet Union wanted to make
the biggest of everything so they made
the biggest hotel and it's like 1500
rooms I don't know it takes a whole
block and uh they just wanted it to be
the the biggest hotel in the in the in
the world and it it it was the biggest
hotel in the room in the
world nobody knew where your room was
nobody none of the rooms had room
numbers on them there there was no uh
food at
all uh in the whole hotel there was no
food and
uh and I suddenly I thought this is
Sara you know like try to understand
that sansara has thousands of rooms in
the hotel and they all suck they're all
terrible okay it doesn't matter you go
to the fifth floor or the first floor
the back or the front or the left or the
right right there's no working Plumbing
the toilet doesn't work there's no room
service the phone doesn't work there's
three guys watching you you know and
this is s no this is real Sara okay you
are just in a tiny tiny little part of
Sara the whole big world your whole big
world is like one piece of dust in Sara
you know and you won't be here long and
you there's a billion places you can go
to people are like will I be with my
cousin when I die
no You' be lucky to be on a planet okay
you might be born in in in the in in the
middle of space many people are and they
just die and they hang out there you
know so be lucky you're on a planet okay
be lucky be you have human beings around
you okay to fight with all right uh it's
better than the other places in this
sansaro
hotel okay it's better you know you're
in a good place the the worst People You
Meet are the sweetest people you will
ever meet in the next thousand
lifetimes okay so try to appreciate okay
try to appre try to appreciate other
human beings they are very rare
and and they don't hurtt you as much as
you will get hurt in other places of
this this hotel every other room is Hell
okay this hotel is not bad the worst
person in your room right now is the
best person you will ever meet in the
next thousand lifetimes okay so come on
you know oh they burned my toast eat
that toast you know next lifetime you
will eat for 100 years burn toast is
pretty good okay
[Music]
uh a person who's
been uh condemned to be
executed tomorrow
morning uh and the the guy comes in and
drags them out and takes that big Axe
and says hold out your hand and you're
like what and they're like we decided
not to cut your head off we're just
gonna cut your hand off oh I love you
thank you so much you know understand
got
it sometimes I think you guys are asleep
you're supposed to get your head cut on
you go out there and the guy big fat guy
with a black suit and he's gonna cut
your head off and he says hold your hand
out and you're like what and he says we
decided just to cut your hand off you
know and then you can go you know that's
called meeting all the [__] you ever
met okay compared to where you could be
it's not so bad okay does it hurt yes is
it like getting your head cut off listen
if that time comes when you have to
choose between your head and your hand
you will happily offer your hand take my
hand take both of them you know I can I
can live but don't cut my head off okay
so listen when you meet a bad person
it's like it's like you're getting your
hand cut okay that's okay that's not so
bad okay just understand there's worse
things all right Tim how much I
got I'm going to class four I'm on
schedule no I'm only 25% behind Okay
let's go one more sentence
so
in Tibet and in India in ancient times
there were some they will actually uh
burn your what do you call Marx abusan
they will burn your skin as a medical
treatment I was a translator for one of
these doctors you know it was fine we
were in Manhattan with rich people put
Golden Needle in the lady's head wrap it
with cotton and set it on fire and she's
like and and the doctor's like no this
is a treatment don't get upset you know
and then he says
here means uh you guys don't know it's a
verb from tarpa so tarwa uh it means to
free to free somebody and it means uh
blood letting to to drain the blood from
a sick person okay so in the old days
they would uh they were very primitive
and they would poke a hole in your arm
and uh drain the blood as a medical
treatment nowadays they just cut the
whole goddamn
thing much more
advanced du
I think a 100 years from now they will
say Do you believe they used to cut
people open can you believe it you know
okay
anyway uh I I went to the doctor I'm
like cut me open he's like I gotta cut
you open sign this
paper I'm I'm about to get anesthesia
I'm in the hospital you were there and
the guy's about to give me the drug and
he says sign this paper I'm listen when
someone asks you to sign a paper paper
before they cut you up read
it so I'm like can I just take a moment
and read it he said no just sign it and
I'm like I'm gonna read it you know and
it says if we find anything else inside
we get to cut that out also without
permission I'm like okay you know that's
okay and what it means is
uh I happily did the surgery because to
not do the surgery was really bad it was
really so the surgery was painful and it
was a lot better than walking around
with this problem for the rest of my
life you see what I mean so every human
being uh if you live long enough you
will have to make tough decisions about
what thing is less painful and which
thing is more painful you see what I
mean and every human being will say cut
please cut you have any more papers I'll
sign all of them you know please cut me
up today you will ask for it uh because
you don't want to die or you don't you
don't want to suffer right you little
suffering is better than dying or or
very serious suffering it's better
what's the example here what's he why is
he talking like that if you answer me
I'll let you go home I'm also going
home huh
yeah Stanley said
[__] yeah putting up with the little
pain of painful people people hurt you
little people who hurt you yeah you
people who say bad things about you
online or or people who who hurt you in
some way then be happy it's like getting
a surgery you know if you can stay happy
with the little pain
with the little pain in the asses all
around you then you can you will not go
to the hell Realms okay got
it yeah you've got cancer okay by the
way I don't have cancer but I'm just
giving an example so someone come up to
you say you have cancer okay do you want
us to cut it out do you want us to try
please it's a nasty operation it will
hurt go for it okay every every
not crazy person will say go for it okay
so that means when you run into Little
irritating people come on you know it's
like surgery got it okay put up with the
little irritating people be nice to
people hurt you okay be nice to people
who say bad things to you and it's like
surgery okay and then you're done I'm
all done I'm done I had all of them he
said you want the ex extra I said yeah
then he finished everything and then I I
said is there anything else he can do he
says Nope I said okay I'm free okay are
you the last [__] I have to deal with
I think so go ahead okay got in okay put
up with the little pain to avoid the
huge pain okay if you want to if you
can't stand it and this person is just
too bad and they keep bothering you then
scream at them yell at them hit them
attack back okay feel good then go to
the hell realm and suffer for a million
years okay what's better the question is
what's better okay what's a it's a good
deal to get cut up if you don't have to
go to the hell Realms got it okay it's a
good deal to put up with really bad
people and be sweet to them and be
patient with them
it's so much better than
going it's so much better than having
cancer spread throughout your whole body
which is called hell real okay got
it all right now there's a special
blessing Diamond wave blessing I will
give
you you will meet an [__] in the next
minutes someone will irritate you in the
elevator someone will step on your foot
someone will kick your
chair your dinner will be
cold and you get to practice patience
okay thank you